NATHAN KANIGSBERG

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

647-226-5542 nathan@kanigsberg.com kanigsberg.dev

<u>nkanigsberg</u>

in <u>nathankanigsberg</u>

PROFILE

I'm a Front-End Developer with an inquisitive and analytical approach to solving problems who always thinks outside the box to find innovative solutions. My entrepreneurial mindset and technical sales experience gives me a well-rounded and insightful perspective, and helps me see the bigger picture.

SKILLS

HTML₅ **jQuery REST APIs** Pair Programming CSS3 React.is Responsive Design Leadership SASS **Firebase** Git & Github Communication JavaScript (ES6) Web Accessibility Team Development Agile Development

EDUCATION

JUNO COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY

Web Development Immersive Bootcamp (2020)

• Also completed Accelerated JavaScript | Accelerated Web Development

RYERSON UNIVERSITY

Computer Science Program (2016-2018)

- 18 credits completed with 4.02 gpa
- experience includes object-oriented and functional paradigms, data structures, with focus on Unix, C and Java

PROJECTS

THEWEATHER

React | REST API | Firebase | Live Link

• React-based weather app using multiple RESTful APIs for data including maps, weather, and location, as well as Firebase for storing user location settings

WATERWORKS

jQuery | jQuery UI | SCSS | Live Link

• Drag-and-drop pipe fitting game built using jQuery and jQuery UI. The board is represented by a 2D array with much of the logic handled by class functions

EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER

Freelance (2018 - present)

 Projects including digital marketing (social media ads, analytics) and building responsive websites for small businesses

TECHNICAL SYSTEMS ANALYST

RBC Technology & Operations (2017)

- Participated in Agile development team working daily with developers as a QA tester and functional consultant
- Designed and presented UI/UX mockups to stakeholders and assisted with project planning & technical documentation

SALES TEAM LEAD

Phantom Screens (2014 - 2016)

- Head of outside sales for one of fastest growing distrubutors worldwide, activities include digital advertising, graphic and web design
- Independently built mobile augmented reality sales tool in Unity and C# to better engage with clients and improve the sales experience

FRANCHISE OWNER

College Pro (2012 - 2013)

 Hired, trained and managed staff of 6-10 and successfully produced over \$160,000 in sales over two years with a net promoter score over 90%